TIWA TAZAMO GRACE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Phone: (+237) 698 400 352

E-mail: gracetiwatazamo@gmail.com

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/grace-tiwa

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

With more than a year experience in software development, I'm able to work independently as well as in a team. My autonomy allows me to work entirely remotely or on site, and to respond to challenges without geographical restrictions.

I always willing to learn and go the extra mile to achieve the organization's goals. I am motivated to join your organization to share my know-how, and I am confident in my ability to contribute to the success of your team in a fast-paced environment.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

March.2023 to date

Software developer, eBOS Remote

Nicosia, Cyprus

- My responsibilities involved leveraging a strong skill set in C#, .NET Framework, MYSQL and ER design, UML diagrams, JQuery and GitHub.
- Contributed to the development and maintenance of the Wisebos platform.
- Designed and implemented a desktop data management application for automated analysis and archiving of employee data.
- Optimization of database procedures and rules for the company's fintech application.
- Regulatory compliance: I have gained experience in implementing software solutions that comply with regulatory requirements such as KYC (Know Your Customer), AML (Anti-Money Laundering) or financial reporting standards. Agile methodologies: we have used agile development methodologies to adapt rapidly to changing market conditions and regulatory requirements.

May 2022 to July 2022 Web Developer Intern, Lahkam

Douala, Cameroon

• We developed a web application for an NGO called Young and Creative whose aim is to showcase the different activities of the NGO and help them receive donations through the platform. Gather, define and translate user requirements into project design.

Aug. 2020 to Nov. 2020 Web Developer Intern, Afrique Média

Douala, Cameroon

• During my internship, our team led the development of the company's website, handling aspects ranging from design to debugging. After the internship, we continued to maintain and support the website for six months.

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND EXPERTISE

C#: Development of robust desktop and web applications.

- Microsoft ASP.NET 6+: Development of secure, scalable web applications.
- WPF: Development of rich user interfaces for desktop applications.
- Tailwind: Use Tailwind CSS to create responsive, personalized user interfaces.
- JavaScript: Developing interactive features for web applications.
- React JS: Creation of dynamic, high-performance web applications.
- JQuery: Simplify DOM manipulation and event management.
- Git, GitHub: Version control management and team collaboration.
- Agile: Management of software development projects using agile methodologies.
- WCF: Creation of web services and communication between applications.
- MVC: Web development architecture for clear separation of concerns.
- Microsoft SQL Server (SQL): Design and management of relational databases.
- Docker: Containerization of applications for increased portability and scalability.
- HTML/CSS: Creation of web page structures and visual styles

EDUCATIONS

2021 - 2022 Bachelor's degree in software engineering

University Institute Gulf of Guinea (Gui)

2020 - 2021 Advanced vocational diploma in software engineering

University Institute Gulf of Guinea (Gui)

LANGUAGES

English proficiency (speaking and writing) French: very professional level

PREVIOUS PROJECTS

Profile Github: https://github.com/tiwagt Profile LinkedIn: https://github.com/tiwagt Profile LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/grace-tiwa

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Integration and business requirements
- Customer systems integration
- Developing and running integration prototypes
- Documentation for Development Team
- Source code awareness
- Incident and problem management
- Department documentation and procedures

References are available on request.